hello and welcome back to another
episode of hermitcraft as you can see
I've put my Minecon cape on I don't know
why I haven't had it on for so long but
it changes the elytra when you have one
look at that I've got a rather weird
looking Iron Golem butterfly thing on my
back I actually have two of these capes
and they are so cool so I'm Gonna Keep
hold of that one I've got the Enderman
one and I've got the Iron Golem one from
London and California as you can also
see well Biff has just decided he was
gonna have a look around my base but
besides that I've made a little bit of
progress I've managed to put all of this
base layer all the way around but I've
pretty much run out of uh White concrete
now it's all gone and there was me
thinking I had loads to go on no that's
it I couldn't even finish the base layer
as you can also see I've started a hefty
potato farm now this potato farm is
isn't actually for me I intend on using
all of these potatoes to trade at the
eye shop or I can't remember exactly
what it's called but it's it's oh look
at that what
excuse me sir
sir
oh something went astray that's why
ha maybe my Redstone is as bad as
everyone says it is
oh well we'll fix that at some point
we've got a lot of potatoes so now it's
time to reap and re-sew I don't know why
this isn't working it should work oh
this just isn't powering that
at all
how peculiar
wait that I don't know what's wrong guys
what am I doing wrong Redstone people
you got you know you guys know exactly
what's going on here I don't I would
have thought this would power that just
as much I just need to make it extend
all the way but I'm just I'm a bit
useless at this it's not that I'm
useless it's that I'm inexperienced I
just don't know the the ways of doing it
that's all I kind of understand how
Redstone works I'm just not very good at
it yet I'm not haven't had enough
experience learning all the little
different tricks so I'm going to quickly
re-sew these so that we can produce a
lot of them there we go
all full now before it was about halfway
maybe a little bit more and that gave me
a stack and a bit to spare as well so
that's going to be useful when trading
with the Villagers this is a design that
x i Azuma VI oid has set me on I'm never
gonna say his name correctly ever again
so it's basically powering all of these
trapdoors to stay up as soon as you hit
the switch they all shut down and they
lower leaving the water to letting the
water go all the way and pushing the
potatoes to the end now this water here
will keep all of this Farmland wet but
this side is not so what I've done is
I've cleverly hidden some of the water
so underneath here there is a
waterlogged slab as you can see behind
every single one so if I delete these
you can see them right there so all
along here this is technically a water
source block meaning that it is giving
all of these Farmland the water that
they need and the best thing is you
can't even see it so this isn't a
permanent Farm by any means this is not
going to stay this way at all because
well I don't do things by half measures
this is just a very temporary thing so I
can get a lot of potatoes the other
thing that I want to show you is the
outside of the base because as I said it
is done well it's all the way around
consistently
but I need your guys opinion on
something because if we go and hop in
the boat so we can get a better View and
do a 180 reveal whoa so you can see the
base of this and this is looking pretty
futuristic this is the sort of thing we
were expecting when we heard futuristic
build am I right so what I've done is
I've filled it in with packed ice and
ice and I was wondering which one is
best but now I'm actually thinking that
it's nice to have the alternate one so
packed ice ice packed ice and that seems
to work really well and I was also
thinking that the entrances could go at
every single side I tell you what though
it does look really strange and I mean
really really strange as it's just
sitting above the water and I originally
was going to create an island of my own
using all the stone I'd got but I've
changed my mind I think it might look
cool if this just slowly goes and hits
the bottom of the sea and then it's just
one big thing and then I can make like
an underwater viewing platform but
that's definitely a tomorrow green
problem that's not a today green problem
I've got some bad news as well guys well
bad news for you good news for me I'm
actually going away for seven days now
that means I won't be able to make any
progress on this now by the time you're
watching this video a few days will have
passed so it just means that the next
episode after this there might not be a
lot done in the meantime because I'll be
relaxing taking a well-earned break but
I seriously will miss working on this
I'm enjoying hermitcraft so much it
makes me really really happy I don't
think I've had this level of Happiness
on YouTube since the start of my YouTube
career and that's really saying
something that really really is so I
just want to thank every single person
that is watching this video honestly so
what are we gonna do today besides fly
around again despite saying that I
wasn't going to fly anymore well I'm
gonna admire the build that we've just
made oh can we get through out no I
really suck at flying I really suck at
flying it's much easier to be fair when
you're in third person so you can see
where you are
but boy is it difficult God God thread
the what
hit that one no I'm determined to get
this now
there we go all right we're gonna do
this properly we're gonna we're gonna go
straight through straight through yes
and street through again yeah nailed it
actually what I'm going to be doing or
part of what we're going to be doing
today is I'm going to have a look around
iskal's base because I saw a video of
his and his base is so unique I really
want a tour around it oh my goodness is
that a Rocket Shop
I need this in my life
I need this oh look they're already
selling a lot whoa he's making killer
money I really really need to start a
shot of some kind oh and he's selling
elytra he sold his for 25 diamonds jevin
sold me his for 20 diamonds so I managed
to save some money there I don't know
what to make a shop on I really oh these
are a bit creepy aren't they the way
that they like chop chop chop jacket
jacket that they could talk that what
would they sound like if they could talk
hello Korean
how are you today
I'm okay
just a head on a wall
anyway I'm getting off track I'm totally
getting off track there he is there's
iskal
hello
are they minor yours are they mine are
yours that I I'm writing it either I
don't really care
I hate Phantoms dude I know right you
can't you're never safe you're never
safe anymore
are you okay there
yeah I was just I'm just I'm just like
there's lots of things going on this guy
was throwing a million tridents as you
can see look at this guy look at this
yeah yeah he's dangerous I wonder if he
can actually hit you it can you see us
because he was just throwing them at
nothing a second ago
I think if you stand up here
he can throw it because I went the AFK
here like only two minutes I went you
know you know I actually do and all of a
sudden I just hear a lot of these things
but he's there okay go on go I'm right
next to him and he's not throwing it at
all
and then he threw like I think 10 in a
row he's legit broken his arm oh
God
we organized to do a little uh base tour
of each other's uh base because we live
like far enough away from each other to
like not really come in contact too much
and I'm excited yeah I really want to
see what you've been what you've been
doing because it is pretty unique from
what I know before we go there though I
have been working on something all day
today I just thought I'd uh thought I'd
let you know that there are some some
available stuff in town now in case you
would need it of course this is what it
is he didn't want a base tour he just
wants to promote his own shot
he just said sell me something oh this
is cool it's like a little Pirate Cave
have you got that so you've got
prismarine and you got sea lanterns this
has all come from this the uh Guardian
farm that you made okay oh so is this is
this is this your base or is this this
is the guardian farm right this is the
guardian Farm okay well I need to tell
everyone what I did yesterday
because go ahead I I well I made a
stupid so I said I kind of died right
and I lost all my levels and iskow
lovingly said
green it's okay we love you you can use
my new Guardian Farm to get XP in a
matter of minutes and he was right but
he just before he left he said don't
pull the lever that's what you said
right yeah that is what I said which you
responded
what does the lever do exactly
but his girl didn't really tell me he
was just like don't worry about it it's
just it's just for keeping the stuff
don't touch it yeah just don't touch it
and then I should have known I I didn't
know I didn't know I've never seen one
of these before so I was like oh how do
I how do I kill stuff so you gotta go
close and like that and I was taking
damage right I was taking damage from
these things so I was like oh I must
have done it wrong I mustn't I'm not
doing it right because I'm taking damage
so I went maybe the lever is on and I
just have to turn it off so I went like
this and then this happened
[Laughter]
oh my goodness oh he did it again
and you died
so what you're supposed to do is just
take a bit of damage that's what I
didn't know you're supposed to take
damage because they have thorns on them
that was my mistake but look at that I
had zero levels
and now I'm on ten instant XP
hey buddy hey great agree and did you
know what happens if you pull the lever
I'm out
what we really came here to do was look
at your your base not sure not do
exactly the same thing I did last night
[Laughter]
well now that we have that done I mean
do you know how much a polar bear weighs
in real life
just in general uh do they have wasted
Minecraft good good point
um I'm gonna guess a couple hundred
kilos
enough to break the ice oh goodness sake
no no you know what I don't even need to
see your base anymore
why did I fall for that why did I fall
for literally the oldest trick in the
book so that wait this is your base oh
you got a nice conduit down here
oh look at this entrance already it
looks like a mine that's been
like submerged I actually say that I'm
glad you say that it's supposed to be
like some kind of yeah overflowed maybe
Ice Age defied ah you got a bit of gold
in here this is so oh my goodness I tell
you what I've seen a few things using
like trap doors and this kind of thing
scar has something kind of similar where
he's got a like a hammock for his bed
and it reminds me of that but this is
really cool
I'm loving this and it's like the little
details with the coral it's like the
little things
I think that's the most important thing
you can build so much but if you don't
put in the details then yeah nothing
nothing pops
okay so this is actually a my
functioning storage room it's not
Redstone I find though
do you get annoyed by the like the
constant swimming
oh I kind of like it with depth Strider
it's it's fine
I yeah I tell you what it's like
building in Creative you get to reach
all the different sites yeah that's true
you get yeah you can access things well
I haven't got depth Strider so I'm
swimming really slowly
but this yeah this is really cool
so you just randomly placing oh my
goodness I thought I was doing all right
there's more to this as well okay oh
okay this is this isn't it there's more
yeah so first did this live in that
stream and I I mean I was thinking there
was a room in there
oh he's frozen solid from lassies so
this is what Brembo
what did you just guess that babe well
it's a dude after the polar bear thing I
I can tell
laughs
yes it's Bramble well I was thinking
it's not going to be like Bumbo isoni
because that's rubbish
yeah yeah no you're right that is the
name rumble recipe is cold and freezing
in that can you explain to my audience
what a Bumbo is
yes a Bumbo is a
um
anything that has that has that has life
that is created to the mustache is a
must but it also has to have an
expression that makes you be it has to
have that what or something that just
brings it to life I don't like builds in
Minecraft that doesn't feel like it has
a story so he's Bumbo squid on I
maybe you get to name him whatever you
want you're here let's take the scallium
right now
and now it's not now it is
no it's not it's just
[Laughter]
it's always a scally you might listen
you will learn eventually you will learn
eventually so have you got more than one
conduit or is it just the one that's
powering all of this no just the one 96
blocks I have another one that I can put
up to solve this is not done but I'm
planning on putting what do you think
about this you swim down here and and
I've kind of dug out the shape of this
room
um but I haven't obviously filled it
with water yet but I'm kind of I I like
that it feels mysterious that this could
be a this could be a tree in the middle
I feel a tree here
yeah like an acacia underwater Roots
like a big Roots no leaves just the
roots yeah you could have yeah I would
say you could like have Roots like
coming down you know kind of oh that's
brilliant as you go through add some
Roots uh like maybe even
fences would work really well
yeah hanging down hanging down yeah I
think that would look real but you would
kind of need to for it to make sense you
might want to put like a tree in a cave
or like above it or something
that would that would really like
complete it I don't know what sort of
space Oh you know what you could do then
you could have well there's space
you could even make a frozen tree up
there you could make like you make it
stuck in ice like like brumbo it's so
cool I love this update I I can't really
fault it to be honest I love it and I
love the Cucumbers the cucumbers are
great the pickles addition pickles
yeah they're great ah
you've just you've just answered the
question that we were aren't we were
asking earlier I showed iskau my list of
things that I want to do and I said what
shop do I want to do I'm gonna make a
pickle shop
I'm gonna make a pickle show I'm gonna
sell pickles
are they gonna be salty because there
are the good pickles and the bad pickles
in life please make them only the finest
pickles okay I can't charge I can't
charge diamonds for pickles unless they
are the best pickles unless they are
that you've ever pickled and I'm gonna
fill it with as many pickle puns and
jokes as I can it's gonna it's gonna be
awful as well it's gonna be like pickle
up two stacks for a diamond or something
like that
yo so you're holding some scallium that
looks a lot like a slime block but like
the ice makes it vanish
oh yes look
what look look how weird that is you're
magical man
that is it's crazy it's weird there's
always been like weird things with like
water and rendering these translucent
blocks but I've never seen like vanish
like that that is completely cut away
and you can see like if you look closely
you can see like a little outline that's
strange that is really odd
anyway I need to head back to my base
because I've still got lots of work to
do thank you so much for the tour and
I'm really looking forward to seeing
where this goes to be honest with you
thank you very much and thank you for uh
for coming by I'm excited to see that
the cake take shape as well I'm I'm
hoping that one day there will be a big
system that connects everyone's base up
so we can like track we can like get
from Base to Base really quickly instead
of having to row for like five minutes
yes I agree 100 anyway I've got to
You're Gonna you're gonna watch me
aren't you but this is embarrassing I'm
gonna watch you I can't do it I can't
dude I can't do it I just you can do it
come on yeah oh you did it
you fly the wrong direction though oh
yeah
I do it okay bye let's go
so that was really cool it was nice to
do a little tour exchange we obviously
haven't got much of a base to show at
this point but it's nice to get an
opinion it's nice to get a little bit of
praise and well especially as I haven't
really got very far I think sometimes I
forget everyone really enjoys the bottle
under the sea the the ship in the bottle
because it's quite a unique idea so I'm
really happy sometimes I forget that
these ideas are are quite cool so now
that the base is pretty much getting
somewhere I need to create one more
Circle and then there's one more thing I
want to do after that but we'll get to
that later we need to just quickly put
this circle together
I've got to just count this perfectly if
this goes off basically if this one
layer is wrong the whole cake could go
completely skew and that is not good so
I'm gonna have to do many many double
checks to make sure that I've got this
right here we go that is a full circle
I think it's perfect everything matched
up it all went in it went pretty well
actually went better than I expected I'm
gonna make this too thick and then this
is actually where the glass starts
coming in so if this is all wrong this
is not good that looks pretty decent I
think
I mean to be honest with you it's hard
to tell if this is going to look good
because well mainly because
it's going to take such a long time to
see what this is going to end up like
but it's a pretty good start I'm pretty
happy with how things have gone so far
it's just made me realize how many
resources I'm gonna need and it's uh
it's kind of difficult that I'm gonna
have an entire seven days where I can't
do anything I always hit my head anyway
to sort of send off this video I'm not
gonna end on a circle of white concrete
would I do that to you on hermitcraft
really
um after the ludicrous display of an
accident that I did with Mumbo
where I dive bombed right into him to
say hello but I I honestly I didn't mean
to kill myself in that situation but I
died
uh so what I thought I'd do is actually
do it intentionally this time so we're
gonna get rid of everything and I mean
everything
and then we're gonna find someone and
we're gonna do a subscribe dive it's
gonna be the last Act of this one before
I go away for a short break so I thought
I'd fill up on blood I'd fill up on
blood I've got my elytra oh I better
repair that before we go actually what
makes this a subscribe dive you say this
is we're going to rename all of the
Redstone to subscribe I'm wasting so
many levels on this I've never done
anything so stupid in my entire life
okay
we're Phil we're full up of our
subscribe subscribe dive look at all
this Redstone you got subscribe dived
we're gonna have to go and pick up in a
light our religion or whatever wherever
we do die but there's only a couple of
people online so hopefully we can find
someone there's recording oh I'm gonna
need a little bit of food
okay so officially Zuma is oh
ow why do I suck so much at elytra
he's at his base at the moment perfect
opportunity
he's right around the corner so we gotta
go way up high we gotta find him
we gotta well we gotta fly around for a
bit and try and get his attention there
he is
there he is so we need to get him to pay
attention to us
for a start but he's he's not looking
look at me give me attention
right let's get rid of the chicken we
only want subscribes here
I'm scared
I did I didn't die I didn't die oh hold
on let's try that again
[Music]
let's try that again
let's try I didn't even die really
all right let's try this again
hello Zuma
I don't think I terribly missed
I think I miss horribly
oh no
[Music]
that was the worst thing I've ever done
anyway everyone thank you very much for
watching I hope you enjoyed this video
and I'll see you in episode seven
goodbye